Speaker 1: sure there's going to be demand for ai but is it worth the money that's going in to all this computer equipment and they're just going to have to keep on replacing it because it becomes obsolete and it's an arms race and if you don't get the latest and best well then you fall behind so yeah even though you spent all this money in the past but that doesn't do it you got to keep spending it all over again so this is
I
Speaker 1: think a
Speaker 2: disaster in the making. Nobody really is thinking about the end game. Everybody is just trying to get in on the action. Everybody wants to outspend everybody else, keep up with the Joneses.
Speaker 1: And as long as the stock prices are going up, the companies are getting rewarded, not based on how much they earn, but based on how much they spend. Because everybody thinks the biggest spender is the biggest winner.
Speaker 1: But they're not. Right now, the companies that win are the companies that are selling the crap that they're buying. But even those companies are going to have a lot of trouble when their customers can't buy anymore because they're broke and they can't borrow anymore. And at some point, the bond market is going to break.
Speaker 3: Earlier today...
Speaker 4: Kevin Warsh testified for the first time as Fed chairman before Congress. Today, he was before the House of Representatives. Tomorrow morning, he'll be before the United States Senate. Before I get into talking about the hearing, and I'm going to spend most of today's podcast discussing this, I want to focus attention on some economic data,
Speaker 4: that was introduced or released
Speaker 5: earlier this morning before the testimony began. And that was the inflation data for June. And the markets, I suppose, were concerned prior to the release that maybe we wouldn't get the good news on inflation.
Speaker 5: that investors had been hoping for, because we had a sell-off in the bond market yesterday. In fact, the yield on the 10-year Treasury got up to 4.62, I believe was the high. And on the 30-year, we got to about 5.11. So these were new highs for this leg of the move up in bond yields.
Speaker 5: and down in bond prices. And I think this is just the beginning of a much bigger move that's coming. Also, we had about $100 an ounce sell-off in gold yesterday. Gold traded back below $4,000 an ounce, although it didn't close below $4,000. But I believe one of the reasons that gold sold off sharply yesterday
Speaker 5: was the
Speaker 4: anticipation of today's inflation report that may not have come in as good as had been hoped. But also, I think traders were trying to price in some type of hawkish statements coming from Warsh during the congressional testimony. So I think they
Speaker 5: wanted to sell gold into these news events. But
Speaker 2: again,
Speaker 2: This still mixes the bigger picture, that inflation is good for gold. It's not bad for gold. But in recent
Speaker 5: years, and I've highlighted it on this podcast how ridiculous
Speaker 1: this is, but the markets react to stronger than inflation news as a sign that the Fed has to fight harder to win the battle against inflation.
And
Speaker 1: gold ends up being collateral damage in that inflation fight because it means the Fed is going to have to hike rates or not cut rates or whatever the markets expect. It means the Fed will be tighter than what it might otherwise have been if the inflation numbers were lower. But all of this misses the bigger picture that the Fed has already lost the inflation battle. That's what all these hotter than expected inflation numbers
Speaker 1: show. And so the fact that inflation keeps coming out worse than expected is not bearish for gold because it means the Fed's going to have to
Speaker 2: fight harder to beat it. It's bullish for gold because it means the Fed can't fight hard enough to beat it and that inflation already won. In fact, I think inflation has been above the Fed's 2% target for almost six years. If the Fed had
the
Speaker 2: the intention or the wherewithal to bring inflation down to 2%, it would have already done
it. The
Speaker 2: fact that it's been talking about it for six years, yet has not achieved this objective, despite constantly predicting that inflation will be back at 2% in two years. And again, I went over in prior podcasts that this prediction is not based on any concrete evidence.
The
Speaker 2: Fed just predicts that inflation will be back to 2% because that's their target. And so they just predict that they're going to achieve their target and they come up with a two year time frame just randomly out of the blue. So it's all just hope, but it never happens. And the reason that inflation is not back
Speaker 6: below 2% is because the Fed can't bring it down to 2% without doing a lot of other things that it doesn't
Speaker 2: want to do.
Speaker 2: And we've been focusing on the fact that Kevin Walsh has said that inflation is a choice. And again, that came up in today's hearing. But it is a choice that Kevin Walsh is going to make. In fact, he's already made that choice. He's just not letting the public know that he's made the choice. He's just BSing them with the rhetoric. But anyway, let me get to the inflation numbers that came out this morning.
Speaker 2: So the expectation
Speaker 7: for inflation in June, headline, was for minus 0.1.
And
Speaker 5: that would be
a big
Speaker 5: improvement over the plus 0.5 from the prior month. We actually got minus 0.4, so a much bigger drop in the May CPI than had been expected.
Speaker 5: Year-over-year, in the prior month, we were at 4.2% year-over-year CPI increase. Because of the lower increase or the drop
Speaker 1: in June, the year-over-year increase is now just 3.5%. So that's a big drop from the prior month, and it's lower than the 3.8%
Speaker 5: that had been expected. Good news there, right, on lower inflation.
And
Speaker 5: the core, ex-Food and Energy, was
Speaker 1: unchanged on the month versus the expected rise of 0.2, which was what we had in the prior month. And the year-over-year core went from 2.9 in May to 2.6 in June. So the markets immediately celebrated. Bond yields fell. Bonds rose. And gold spiked $100 an ounce.
Now,
Speaker 1: first of all, it's not even really good news on inflation because
Speaker 5: the main driver of the 0.4 percent drop was the oil price decline. Oil was down about 30 percent in May. Why? Well, because supposedly the war with Iran was over.
We
Speaker 5: had the MOU, we had the ceasefire, so oil prices went down
Speaker 1: 30%. Well, now the ceasefire is off, the war is back on, and oil prices, which are now back up at $80 a barrel as of right now, oil prices are up 20% so far in July. So July is only half over. It's possible that the entire...
Speaker 1: drop
Speaker 7: in oil prices that we enjoy in May, or in June rather, because the
Speaker 6: war was off, are going to be taken away in July because the war is back on. So why even celebrate what really
Speaker 7: amounts to a meaningless number? What's more important is that we're way above 2%.
And
Speaker 7: we're not going to get anywhere near two percent,
Speaker 6: no matter what the Fed does. And of course, what's more problematic is that these are the government numbers,
Speaker 7: the official government measures of inflation, which maybe capture half of the actual price increases that Americans are forced to endure. Now, gold gave up about half of its hundred dollar gain.
Speaker 7: by the end of the day. I think gold ended up closing up about 50 bucks on the day. We closed just above 4,050. Silver up about a dollar, closing at 58.58. It got clobbered a couple of bucks yesterday.
Speaker 6: But I think the most significant action was in the bond market because the bond market lost almost the entire gain.
Speaker 6: By the end of the day, the yield on the 30-year Treasury was back up to
Speaker 1: 5.1.
And the
Speaker 1: 10-year is back to 4.59. So almost the high watermarks,
Speaker 5: despite...
this
Speaker 5: better than expected inflation number. Now, one of the reasons there could be some nervousness surrounding tomorrow's release of the PPI. We're going to get that tomorrow morning before we get day two up on Capitol Hill. And the producer prices have been coming in a lot hotter than consumer prices. Of course,
The
Speaker 5: producer prices are also going to benefit from the drop in oil prices that we had last month, which is pretty much being undone this month. So again, I don't know why the markets would pay attention to such backward-looking data that is really
Speaker 2: irrelevant, but that's what they do. And this is how these algorithms are programmed, and they trade off the numbers. I just think that people should take advantage of any
Speaker 7: of these moves.
Speaker 7: In fact, when people believe that inflation, higher inflation, is bad for gold, when in fact gold is an inflation hedge, and the more inflation we have, the more you need to hedge yourself, should take advantage of this misguided idea that higher inflation is somehow bad for gold because it means the Fed has to fight harder to bring inflation down. What it really proves is that
inflation,
Speaker 7: the Fed can't bring inflation down. It doesn't have the wherewithal or the ability to do it because of all the other problems that would be exposed if the Fed were to do that. And that kind of brings me to the discussion of today's hearing before Congress. And what's the most frustrating part, of course, about the entire hearing.
Speaker 7: is that they're there to discuss
Speaker 6: inflation. And nobody, except maybe Walsh, but he doesn't want to let the cat out of the bag, but the entire discussion centers around a term that nobody properly defines. Everybody acts as if inflation is rising prices. And it's not, I've talked about it on this podcast many times. Inflation is an expansion.
of
Speaker 6: the supply of money and credit. That is what is being inflated. You can't inflate a price, you inflate money supply because inflate means to expand.
And if you're gonna
Speaker 6: have a discussion about inflation, but you're misdefining what the term means, then your whole discussion is meaningless. Because prices go up, prices go down. Inflation is a whole different problem
Speaker 6: that causes the general price level to be higher than what it otherwise would have been absent the inflation. It
doesn't even
Speaker 6: mean that prices go up. It can simply mean that inflation prevented prices from going down. Now, again, the government tries to tell us that prices going down would be horrible because
Speaker 6: How would it be horrible, especially when so many people are suffering from high prices? Look how much food prices have gone up over the past several years. Would it be such a disaster if they came down? Of course not. I mean, why do they have to keep going up? If the problem is food prices are too high, having a target of, well, let's have them go up another 2% a year, that doesn't solve the problem.
Speaker 6: of prices being too high. That makes them higher. What would solve the problem is if prices actually came down. And that would solve a lot of problems. Consumers want the price of everything to go down. Yet according to the government, that would be a disaster. The government is there to make sure that prices don't go down, to save us.
Speaker 6: from the pain of being able to buy stuff for less, right? This is what the government is selling us on. So that's the biggest problem is a misunderstanding of the term. But then the other thing that really frustrates me, always about these hearings, is
that you've
Speaker 6: got all these congressmen and women that
are upset
Speaker 6: about inflation, and they're asking the Fed, what are you going to do about it? What's your plan? How are you going to stop disinflation?
Speaker 6: Meanwhile, they are part of the reason that we have inflation. It takes two to do the inflation tango. Congress has to spend money it doesn't have. It has to have deficits. And then the Fed monetizes those deficits. And the Fed artificially suppresses interest rates in large part.
Speaker 6: To make it possible for the government to finance those deficits without having a crowding out effect on private credit and pushing up interest rates. So it is the Congress and, of course, the president, because he's signing on to all this spending and the Fed. It's a combination of monetary and fiscal policy working hand in glove. That is why.
There
Speaker 6: is inflation. Yet the very congressmen and women that are voting for the deficit spending that is ultimately the source of the Fed, of the inflation that the Fed creates, they're there yelling at the Fed as if they have nothing to do with it. They need to look in the mirror.
Speaker 6: and recognize their own responsibility. And then, of course, the Fed, Fed chairs, they always deny their responsibility. They want to blame tariffs. They want to blame the war. They want to come up with all kinds of excuses about where inflation is coming from. The cause of inflation is right there in that hearing. It is being caused by all the representatives and the Fed.
Speaker 6: They're there discussing a problem that they've created and they're pretending that there's some exogenous solution.
And and then
Speaker 6: when Warsh talks about how, oh, we're going to do things differently, we're going to solve the problem without actually getting into what would need to be done to solve the problem.
Speaker 6: Which is why they're not going to solve the problem. Anyway, we've got a quick commercial break, so stick around. As soon as we come back, I'm going to get into the hearing and the Q&A.
Speaker 8: Talk to any manufacturer in this country right now, and you'll hear
the same thing. The
Speaker 8: pressure is coming from every direction. Rising energy costs, a tight labor market, supply chains that are still fragile, and cyber threats that get worse every quarter. This isn't one problem you can solve and move on. Rockwell Automation just put out
there
Speaker 8: 11th annual state of smart manufacturing report. They surveyed over 1,500 decision makers across 17 countries, and what they found is exactly what you'd expect if you've been paying attention. 90% of
manufacturers
Speaker 8: say digital transformation isn't optional anymore. It's the price of staying competitive. But here's where it gets interesting. Only 43% of the data these companies collect is actually being used. The rest just sits there. That's enormous value left on the table, and nearly half of them, 46%, were hit by a cyber incident in just the past year. As factories get more connected, that risk lands directly
Speaker 8: on the balance sheet. If you run a manufacturing business or you invest in one, this report is worth your time. Download it for free at rok.auto/sosm. That's rok.auto/sosm.
Speaker 4: All right. So the first thing that Chair Warsh said that really caught my attention
Speaker 1: was when he talked about how many people work at the Federal Reserve.
Speaker 1: I mean, I never really thought about how many people work there. I had no idea it was 23,000. The Federal Reserve employs 23,000 people. What the hell do these 23,000 people do?
why
Speaker 1: do we need 23,000 people to set interest rates? I mean, you know, one person should be able to do it. You know, there's what, there's 13 members of the FOMC that vote. I don't know where all these people are coming from. First of all, the Fed shouldn't even be involved in setting interest rates. The free market should do that. So we don't really need any employees. But 23,000 people
at
Speaker 1: the Fed? I mean, talk about inflation, right? We've had an inflation in the number of people who work at the Fed.
When the
Speaker 1: Federal Reserve first opened its
Speaker 2: doors for business, it was November 2nd, 1914. I looked this up. I mean, I knew that the Federal Reserve Act was passed in 1913, like,
you
Speaker 4: know, like this income tax, right? It was a horrible year for America. It was a twofer.
Speaker 4: Because we got the income tax and the Federal Reserve during the same year. So, you know, 1913 is probably the worst year in U.S. history as far as bad legislation. But I looked it up.
We the
Speaker 4: Fed didn't start its operations until the following year, right? Because they had to set it up. Once the Federal Reserve Act authorized the creation of the
Speaker 1: Fed, they had to set it up. So they opened for business.
Speaker 1: November 2nd 1914 on that day they had 40 employees that's it so 40 people were able to do the entire job that
the
Speaker 5: Federal Reserve was created to perform here we are over a hundred years later and it doesn't take 40
Speaker 1: people it takes 23,000 people to do the job
Speaker 1: This shows you, in and of itself, is a reason to get rid of the entire institution.
Because 100
Speaker 1: years ago, or more than 100 years ago, in 1914, they didn't have any computers. I mean, they didn't have any of the
Speaker 2: labor-saving devices that we have today. I mean, they didn't even have carbon paper, I don't think. I mean, they had a typewriter. They didn't have photocopy machines. I mean, what did they have
Speaker 1: back then?
You
Speaker 1: know, yet with the technology that was available in 1914, it only took 40 people to run the Federal Reserve. If that was the case, we should just need one now.
The problem is
Speaker 1: the Federal Reserve is doing so many things that it was not created to do.
That's why there's
Speaker 1: 23,000 people there. We're wasting all this money.
Speaker 1: We're wasting all the human resources. In fact, one of the things that maybe AI can do, I would like to abolish the Fed, but if we're not going to abolish it, why not just automate the entire thing? Why not just have a AI agent do all the monetary policy, just program it up, fire all 23,000 people?
And
Speaker 1: just let, you know, Claude, you know, or XAI do the whole thing, right? We'd save a fortune. You know, my dad used to joke that we could replace the entire FOMC with a bunch of parrots because they really don't do much, right? Cut interest rates, expand credit, you know, print money, right? There's not that much that they could actually do. So we could train some parrots to do the job. But
Speaker 4: anyway, so I thought that initially stuck out.
Speaker 4: that there were 23,000 people. Fed's got to be one of the biggest employers in the country, 23,000 people. Anyway, so one of the, I think, important admissions that Warsh made, and this is something that, you know, I was not a Monday
Speaker 1: morning quarterback here. I was criticizing this policy in real time as the mistakes were being made, not just
Speaker 2: here in the US, but in Europe.
Speaker 2: in Japan. Warsh admitted, in hindsight,
that
Speaker 1: a key mistake that the Fed made was that it attempted to raise the inflation rate. They were trying to get a little bit more inflation and that the
Speaker 1: That was the reason that we ended up with a lot more inflation and that that was a dangerous policy to deliberately try to raise the inflation rate, which is what I was saying for years.
It shouldn't
Speaker 1: be that 2% is a target.
2% should be
Speaker 1: the ceiling, which again is where the 2% number came from. It was introduced in New Zealand.
The
Speaker 1: first central bank to have an inflation ceiling of 2%. How that ever became a target, I don't know. It didn't mean that if inflation was 1%, you had to work to get it to 2%. It meant that as long as it was under 2%, it was OK. 1% was better than 1.5% because you were further beneath the ceiling.
But
Speaker 1: as the inflation rate got close to 2%, if it got to 1.8, 1.9, that would mean you'd have to act. Because if you didn't act, it might get above 2. But the way we were conducting monetary policy, the way the ECB was conducting monetary policy, if we were 1.8, that wasn't enough. That the central bank had to tweak the rate up to 2%, which was ridiculous.
Speaker 1: If you're at 1.8%, why not leave well enough alone? Hey, we're pretty close to 2%. Why risk going over 2%?
And
Speaker 2: in fact, we even made it worse in the US. And I criticize this real time. When we got a little bit above 2%, the Fed came up with an asinine approach called inflation averaging and said, we now have to make up for all the years of being below 2%, which
Speaker 2: We now need to run above 2% for a little bit to average the inflation down, which at the time I said was complete nonsense. And Kevin Walsh now agrees with that. Why should we have to
Speaker 5: tell Americans, look, because you got lucky for a few years and your prices only went up by 1.8% a year?
or not
Speaker 5: lucky you got gypped right you didn't get the two percent inflation that we promised you you got ripped off and your cost of living only went up 1.8 percent so now we're going to get you even now we're going to we're going to make sure you get 2.2 percent inflation for a while so you can get the two percent average that you're hoping for right that that's effectively what they were saying but i said real time okay
you're
If
Speaker 5: they're going to target an average rate of inflation of 2%, what are they going to do when inflation is way above 2% and now it requires inflation below 2% to bring the
Speaker 2: average down? I said, are they going to target an inflation rate below 2%? No. What did they do with inflation averaging? They tossed it, right? As soon as it became inconvenient, they abandoned the whole concept, which means they're
Speaker 2: And this is what I said at the time. The real goal was to enable more inflation. So they made up this BS that they had to average inflation up. But the minute the shoe was on the other foot and they needed to average inflation down, forget about it. Oh,
Speaker 5: we don't want average inflation anymore. We just want to bring it down to 2%. No matter how many years it's above 2% and no matter how far above
Speaker 1: 2% it is, meaning if it's at 10%,
For
Speaker 1: three, four, five years in a row, our goal
is not
Speaker 1: to try to average it down. We just want to bring future
Speaker 5: inflation to 2%. So the minute you get way above 2% trend, I mean, you're never going to get back down, which shows that
Speaker 1: the whole policy is nonsense. And of course, there's all sorts of reasons, and I've gone over that over time.
Speaker 1: that the 2% target is all a bunch of BS. It was all about justifying inflation, and the only time the Fed
Speaker 5: ever had a 2% target was when they were below it. So they can use it as an excuse to have higher inflation. We never had a 2% target when it was 4 or 5
or 6%. The
Speaker 7: Fed invented it. Now, of course, they made that bed, and now they got a lie in it, which they can't. Now, another thing
Speaker 1: that Warsh talked
about
was
Speaker 1: regime change at the Fed. Now, he's using this word, right? Not me, right? He's talking about regime change, meaning that he's the new regime. Well, you know, the regime change at the Fed is about as legitimate as the regime change in Iran because nothing has changed. I don't care how different people think Warsh is or how much of a difference he wants to create by putting distance in Iran.
Speaker 1: between himself and his predecessors, although
he
Speaker 4: had nothing but kind words to say for Alan Greenspan, who recently passed away. And I mentioned that in a past podcast. But no
Speaker 1: matter how much he wants to say that there's been regime change, it's the same regime. Nothing has changed now.
Speaker 1: Warsh is trying to pretend that things have changed because he's hoping that that will make his job easier, that somehow pretending that he's going to succeed
Speaker 2: where Powell failed, that somehow that's going to placate the markets, that maybe we're going to get lower bond yields or a stronger dollar just based on the fact that he's saying that he's different, even though what he's doing proves that he's exactly the same. Right.
Speaker 2: The only way that regime change at the Fed would actually work to lower inflation is if we also got regime change in Congress and at the White House, and we're not getting that. Again, Congress is demanding lower inflation while at the same time running massive deficits that are producing the inflation. You can't have it both ways. You can't run massive deficits.
Speaker 2: and then complain about inflation because the inflation is what's necessary to finance those deficits. Now, of course, that is why Congress helped redefine inflation. So they can do that. So they can promote and vote for these big spending bills to pretend
Speaker 1: that you get something for nothing and then rail against inflation because the public doesn't understand that the deficit spending is the cause of inflation because it results
Speaker 1: in the expansion of the money supply because if the Congress isn't taking the money from you in taxes, it has to get the money somewhere. It gets it from the Fed. The Fed expands the money supply. The Fed creates inflation to cover the spending. And so inflation is your tax. And on multiple occasions, Warsh referred to inflation as a tax. That is why it's a tax.
Speaker 2: It pays for government spending.
Speaker 2: So they can't have their cake and eat it, too, although that's what they try to do by lying about what inflation is. So because there's been no regime change, inflation is not going to change. It's going to continue to get worse, just like it has in the past. We aren't going to go anywhere near 2% inflation. I don't care how
Speaker 5: many times Warsh wants to say that he will deliver price
Speaker 2: stability, he will deliver it.
It
Speaker 2: isn't going to happen. And in fact, he doesn't even know how to define price stability because he came up with his own definition of price stability. And what he said was that price stability is when prices go up by an amount that's not too large that people worry about it, that they talk about it, that they complain about it. That's the definition of price stability? No, it's not.
Price
Speaker 2: stability means stable prices. I mean, look up stable in the dictionary. What does it say? Stable means the same. They remain the same. Price stability is not prices that rise, just not enough for you to complain about it. And the problem is Americans...
Speaker 2: Because begin to accept inflation as the way of life as like the cost of capitalism So just because Americans get used to and accept high inflation and so they don't complain about it anymore That doesn't mean that you know, they can't the feds got a green light to keep creating it No price stability means prices that remain stable. It doesn't mean prices going up. Just not so much that you're worried about it
Speaker 6: Whether you're worried about it or not and of course as I said earlier
Speaker 6: Sometimes inflation stops prices from going down, and that is a bad thing. A lot of people don't realize that prices would have gone down. They're robbed of that benefit that they never even realized they were going to get. Inflation, the government steals the benefit of falling prices right out from under us. So we don't even realize that the cost of living would have been lower.
Speaker 6: Because the
Speaker 7: government created inflation that prevented prices from going down, which would have meant our standard of living would
Speaker 9: have gone up. Anyway, I got another commercial break and I'm going to keep on talking about this and a couple more topics on the other side of the break.
Speaker 9: so stick
Speaker 8: around. I've been in the investment business my entire life. One of the most common mistakes that I see is when people treat life insurance like an investment. That's the wrong way to think about it. Life insurance exists to protect the people who depend on you financially if you are not around
to do
Speaker 8: it yourself. That's why term is the right answer for most people.
Speaker 8: it gives you the biggest death benefit for the smallest premium. And that frees up the rest of your money to make actual investments. Investments that will perform a lot better than the cash value sitting inside a whole life policy, which inflation is gonna chew through anyway. And the longer you wait, the more it costs. So the rational move is to handle it now,
Speaker 8: While it's cheap and while you don't need it, that's where ethos comes in. The whole process is online. You can get a quote in seconds and apply in just minutes. You can get up to $3 million in coverage, and some policies start as low as $30 a month. Ethos makes getting life insurance fast and easy, 100% online. You can get a quote in seconds, apply in minutes, and
get a quote in seconds.
Speaker 8: and get same-day coverage. There's no medical exam. Just answer a few simple health questions. Take 10 minutes to get covered today with life insurance through Ethos. Get your free quote at ethos.com/gold. That's ethos.com/gold. Application times and rates may vary. All right, I am
Speaker 1: discussing day one of the Kevin Warsh congressional testimony, day two with the U.S. Senate tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of going over some of the key points. And by the way, I'm just scrolling through my X page because in real time, as I'm listening to this testimony, I'm like firing off posts. Now, some of the posts I put on
Speaker 4: after the fact because I'm trying to space them out a bit. But another reason why, if you're not following me on X, you should follow me. And I write all these posts myself. I don't have somebody else doing it for me. These are my thoughts.
as
Speaker 4: they come to mind. And I'm putting them out
Speaker 1: there. I'm less than 10,000 followers from 1.6 million now. Like I said, I'm adding about 100,000 followers a month. So the pace at which I'm gaining followers has been picking up, which I take it as a good sign. More people are listening to me. So if you're not a follower
Speaker 2: on Axe, make sure and follow me. And then
Speaker 2: Repost my stuff. Every time I post something, repost it, like it, comment on it, because that will draw more attention to it, and more people will
Speaker 1: get to know the truth. Because the truth is coming from me. There's so many lies coming from so many other sources. It's good to get the
Speaker 4: truth. Okay, so another thing... Okay, so again, I'm reading just from my own posts to remind myself of what I want to discuss here.
Speaker 4: So, again, very frustrating
Speaker 2: that Walsh is not holding the members of Congress accountable for their role in creating inflation. And probably
Speaker 1: that's because when you live in a glass house, you don't throw stones. Right. So why should Walsh?
Speaker 1: accuse Congress of creating inflation when they can turn around and do the same thing so everybody pretends that neither of the other party is responsible meanwhile they both share responsibility but this is a bunch of theater for the public although one of the things that the Democrats tried to do and
you know
Speaker 9: Warsh didn't want any part of it and he was you know very easily sidestepping this and
Speaker 5: the the
Speaker 5: The Democrats had valid points here. I agreed with all the points they made. They were just making them in the wrong form. But they were trying to get worse to condemn Donald Trump for his grifting, for the $2.2 billion that he made
Speaker 7: ripping off the public and exploiting the presidency for his own personal gain. I mean, Donald Trump and the Trump family could not have made anywhere near $2 billion last year.
Other than
Speaker 7: Trump being president, it was the fact that he was president that gave him the popularity to dump all these meme coins and to make all this money and to generate all the hype and hysteria surrounding not only the meme coins, but, you know, his his his stocks and all that. And there's a lot of other dealings. There's a lot of articles that have now been written really exposing Trump.
Speaker 7: What the Trumps have done and the Republicans look like complete hypocrites because they criticize the Bidens, yet they're looking the other way when the Trump's outbiding the Bidens by a wide margin. But you had the congressman trying
Speaker 6: to get worse to condemn the president, which he's not going to do. Trump just appointed
Speaker 7: the guy. He's not going to start picking a fight with him. It was the wrong place to bring this stuff up.
Speaker 7: But the points were valid and also the conflicts of interest with, you know, Trump regulating. In fact, you know, the court threw out the settlement that Trump made with himself, which I criticized the day I read about it. You know, Trump sued the IRS for, I don't know, $10 billion because a subcontractor, not even the IRS itself, a subcontractor leaked some information.
from
Speaker 7: his tax return. And so sues for $10 billion. What
the IRS
Speaker 6: did to Trump was nothing compared to what they did to me. Because in my case, it was the IRS itself that leaked information. And they leaked information about a grand jury investigation, a criminal investigation about me. That was supposed to be top secret. That was leaked.
and
Speaker 6: caused me real damage. Trump didn't get any damage from that leak. Where was he damaged? I mean, he didn't have any damages. I had actual damages. My whole business was destroyed because the IRS leaked confidential grand jury information to the media. Yet when
I file
Speaker 6: a lawsuit, that gets thrown out of court. I get nothing. I mean, I filed an appeal, but who knows, I might lose that.
But
Speaker 6: I had real damages caused by an actual IRS leak. Trump doesn't have any damages, but then he negotiates the settlement with himself. He runs the IRS. And so he gets this sweetheart deal where his entire family now can't be audited, can't be fined, is totally forgiven for any past offense that they may have had with respect to taxes.
You
Speaker 6: know, all you know, all their businesses that they're related enterprises, the whole family, the kids, the IRS can't touch them. Right. Who knows what they've done? I'm sure they've done a lot. That's why they they did this. But the court correctly threw out this settlement by saying there was no adversary party. You can't settle something with yourself. Donald Trump.
was
Speaker 6: in charge of the iris he negotiated a deal with himself and so of course he came out with a
Speaker 9: great thing but this didn't even come up really in the hearing but i had this was a news story that came out this week that the court threw this thing out um but anyway so i digress let me get back uh to to the hearing now a comment that warsh made that i thought was ridiculous and i you know he's supposedly a smart guy and he is a smart i'm not saying he's not smart
But
Speaker 9: clearly, maybe he doesn't completely understand monetary policy, which, again, is part of the criteria for being Fed chairman, right? You've got to, you know, they give you a test on economics, and only the people who fail the test are considered as candidates to be at the Fed or to chair the Fed. But Wors said that he prefers using interest rates
as
Speaker 7: a monetary policy tool than the Fed's balance sheet.
And I
Speaker 7: don't like either. And I especially don't like the balance sheet. So I would agree with with Walsh there that the Fed should not be using its balance sheet at all. It should reverse all the quantitative easing. But he said the reason that he prefers interest rates is because he says that doesn't favor one class over another. Of course it does. I mean, first of all, yes, QE obviously favors interest rates.
Speaker 7: the class who owns the assets that the Fed is buying, right? So if the Fed is using its balance sheet to bail somebody
out by
Speaker 7: buying up some toxic asset that they own, right, they're obviously benefiting. But artificially low interest
Speaker 6: rates also have clear winners and losers. Who wins from low interest rates?
Speaker 7: Debtors. The debtors win. Who loses? The creditors.
Speaker 7: They lose. So it absolutely does pit one interest against another. It favors the debtor relative to the saver, especially wealthy leveraged debtors who have borrowed to accumulate assets. They really win because it makes it cheaper for them
to
Speaker 6: borrow, and then inflation wipes out
the
Speaker 6: value of what they owe. So they're winners. The losers are the savers, which tend to be more of the middle class. And even if middle class don't have a lot of savings anymore because taxes and inflation have pretty much wiped it out, they still have pensions, annuities, cash value
Speaker 7: and an insurance policy. They have a lot of saving vehicles that get harmed by inflation.
But
Speaker 7: also, who benefits from artificially low interest rates? The government, the federal government. The government is the biggest debtor of them all. So the government wins,
Speaker 6: but the savers, the people who bought government bonds, the people who loan money to the government, they're losing, right? They're getting a lower return. And who owns a lot of those government bonds? Insurance companies own those government bonds.
And
Speaker 6: that means they have to charge higher
Speaker 7: premiums to Americans who are buying fire insurance, life insurance, car insurance, because they're not getting as high a yield on their bonds. They have to charge higher premiums to their customers.
Speaker 6: So that's another way that the middle class suffers from artificially low interest rates. And the government...
Speaker 6: benefits and other debtors from the ability
Speaker 7: to borrow. So I don't know if Walsh actually believes this. This is a very simple point. Does he not understand that there are two parties to a loan? There's the lender and there's the borrower. And that if you advantage one, you disadvantage the other. Does he not get the distinction there? I don't know. But that's what he said. And I
was
Speaker 7: That he made a comment that was that incompetent. Now, another point that I wish he would have made more clear had
to do
Speaker 7: with
Speaker 4: black workers. And, you know, whenever there's one of these hearings, inevitably you get an African-American representative, typically.
Speaker 2: asking the Fed chairman, what are you going to do specifically to help African-Americans? And in this case, it was African-American workers who this representative claimed were disproportionately impacted by rising unemployment or
Speaker 5: inflation, whatever it was. But she kept saying, what are you going to do specifically to help African-Americans? Now, Warsh just ignored her question.
Speaker 5: which
Speaker 2: probably upset her, which is why she asked it a couple of times. But I wish he would have just had the courage to be more candid and actually reply and say, you know something, Congresswoman? There's nothing we could do. I understand you're concerned about the plight of black workers, but
the Fed
Speaker 2: can't do anything about it.
Like we
Speaker 2: can we can change interest rates.
But
Speaker 2: how does that affect a black worker versus a white worker or a Hispanic worker? I mean, they're all the same, right? We have, you know, a couple of levers, right? Print money, don't print money, cut rates, raise rates. There's no, you know, lever that we can pull for African-Americans.
Speaker 1: There is no specific policy that.
Speaker 1: can be targeted. Why not just tell her that? Why not just level with her and say, look, you know, this is not the place where he's afraid. He's afraid to speak up. You know, nobody
Speaker 2: wants to criticize anybody for asking these ridiculous questions. But even better, what I would love to see Kevin Walsh do is say, you know what, Congresswoman, I appreciate that you're concerned about black workers and,
Speaker 7: you know, the problems that they're facing.
Why
Speaker 7: don't you do something about it legislatively? Why don't you start repealing a lot of the laws
that
Speaker 2: Congress has passed over the decades that are disadvantaging African-American workers? They are being disproportionately impacted by all the war on poverty, great society, welfare programs starting from the 1960s.
Speaker 2: And all of the laws, the anti-discrimination laws that have been passed have backfired. Everything the government has done to help African-Americans has backfired and harmed them. It's
Speaker 5: got nothing to do with the Fed. Yeah, I mean, the Fed harms everybody, right? They're an equal opportunity harmer. Their bad
Speaker 2: monetary policy and their inflation, sure. And you can say, well, if blacks are disproportionately
wealthy
Speaker 2: poor and middle class, then maybe they disproportionately suffer relative, you know, from inflation, which may be true. But there's no way that the Fed could target that relief to the African-Americans. It is he could just paint with one big brush.
But if
Speaker 6: Congress actually repealed a lot of these laws that, you know, maybe they were well-intentioned, I'll
Speaker 2: give them that they had well-intentioned.
Speaker 2: But, you know, the road to hell is paved with good intentions. And in this case, it's the African-Americans who are in hell as a result of that well-intentioned legislation. Now, in many cases, it wasn't well-intentioned. The actual purpose of the legislation was to trap African-Americans in poverty to secure their votes so that they can hold out an escape from poverty and,
Speaker 2: you know, kind of as bribes or to get African-Americans to depend on government handouts so that they'll keep voting for the people who are writing the checks that they're cashing, right? The government breaking your leg so that you'll rely on them for a crutch. So in many cases, again, it isn't good intentions. It's evil intentions. But in some cases, yeah, I'm sure there are members of Congress who are foolish enough to
Speaker 5: actually think that these programs are going to help.
Speaker 5: Well, they don't help. They hurt. That's why,
Speaker 1: you know, conservatives and libertarians are opposed to them. Now, they could also be opposed to them for constitutional and moral reasons, but they're
Speaker 2: also opposed to them because they know they don't work. They understand the unintended consequences that the left completely ignores. So Warsh would have had an opportunity to shove that in her face. But, you know, he doesn't want to do that.
Speaker 9: Anyway,
Speaker 9: Um, I'm going to talk more about, uh, the congressional testimony on my second podcast later this week, because then we're going to have, uh, the, uh, the Senate version and we'll have the full market reaction, uh, to, to what's been said.
A couple more points I wanted to make
Speaker 9: though, in this podcast, one, I want to talk about
Speaker 4: this AI bubble.
Speaker 4: And I've been talking about the AI bubble for a while, and I happened to watch a George Gammon video that, you know, kind of made this point. And so I wanted to credit George because I did watch it. And, you know, if you see this video on YouTube, you could check it out because he has some really good graphs that really show this. And I'm not, you know, putting up any graphs in my podcast.
Speaker 4: But a lot of
Speaker 2: people say, oh, there's no AI bubble. It's nothing like the dot-com bubble. And they look at companies like NVIDIA, and they say, look, their PEs aren't that bad. They're making a lot of money, unlike the dot-com companies that weren't making any money. And that may be true, that NVIDIA is making money. But you have to look at the source of those profits. Where are they coming from?
The
Speaker 2: customers who are spending all this money are basically losing a fortune. So NVIDIA's gains simply come at the expense
Speaker 1: of the hyperscaler's losses. Now, up until now, they're not really reporting losses. They still have income because the expenditures are CapEx. And because they're CapExs,
Speaker 1: They don't reduce EBITDA, right? The main earnings numbers, earnings before interest, dividends, depreciation, all that stuff. What Wall Street focuses on, they don't look at depreciation. They just look at the cash numbers.
And
Speaker 2: CapEx is excluded. But these big companies, Meta and Amazon and Google and now SpaceX, a lot of these companies initially, maybe not SpaceX, but had a lot of cash.
Speaker 2: Because Google and Amazon, they had a lot of cash on their balance sheets. Well, they used that cash to build out the
Speaker 6: data centers and to buy all these GPUs and other semiconductors, whatever they needed. But once they burned through the cash, then they had to use their earnings. But now they're resorting to debt. They have borrowed tens of billions, hundreds of billions, maybe over 100 billion already has been borrowed.
in
Speaker 6: the bond market. So these big cash cows have turned into cash vacuums. They're now sucking up cash by going to the credit markets and borrowing tremendous amounts of money, which is not only going to drive up the interest cost of what they have to borrow, but it's going to drive up the interest cost of what everybody has to pay, because there's only so much savings to go around.
Speaker 6: And if now you have these once cash cows now sucking up cash, now you have companies that weren't borrowing any money, that were lending money, right? Meta was lending money. Google was, they were buying treasuries. They were lenders. Now they're massive borrowers because they're borrowing a fortune to pay for all this CapEx.
Speaker 6: This is also what's pushing up interest rates, crowding out the market. You've got the government borrowing more. You've got these companies borrowing more. But the other problem is now these companies are losing money if you actually count what they're spending. And especially if you consider the depreciation.
Speaker 7: Now, I know that they're probably depreciating the GPUs and stuff over five or six years. But yeah.
that
Speaker 7: those losses are not really being recognized by the market because they're, you know, they're looking beyond that. But in reality,
Speaker 6: the life cycle of this equipment is more like two to three years. It becomes obsolete very quickly. And so the money that's being spent is not really like
Speaker 6: capital investment
Speaker 7: where you spend the money and now you've got something for 20 or 30 years that you could use. You're
spending
Speaker 6: money and you're going to have to spend it all over again in two or three years. That's really not like capital investment. That's more like the cost of doing business. That's like an operating expense. That's really what all this is. These big hyperscalers are spending a fortune and losing money. They are not making money on their AI products.
Speaker 6: Yes, there's a lot of demand for these products because they don't cost very much. Even the premium services, where they may be $100 or $200 a month, they're still pricing that at a loss. But you've got a lot of people that are using for whatever, $10, $20 a month. They're losing a ton of money on that. And then there are other people that use AI for free. When you go to Google...
Speaker 6: Right. And you use their A.I., you search A.I. and ask. You don't have to pay anything. It's all free, but it's not free to Google. Google is spending a lot of money on the compute that makes its A.I. work, but it's not charging anybody anything. You know, and they look at the demand. Oh, we got all this demand for A.I. Sure. Because you're giving it away. I mean, you get plenty of demand for stuff when it doesn't cost any money.
Speaker 6: The problem is, are these hyperscalers ever going to make any money on what they're spending?
Sure,
Speaker 1: there's going to be demand for AI, but is it worth the money that's going in to all this computer equipment? And they're just going to have to keep on replacing it because it becomes obsolete and it's an arms race. And if you don't get the latest and best, well, then you fall behind.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, even though you spent all this money in the past, but that doesn't do it. You got to keep spending it all over again. So this is, I think, a disaster
Speaker 2: in the making. You know, nobody really is thinking about the end game. Everybody is just trying to get in on the action. Nobody, everybody wants to outspend everybody else. Keep up with the Joneses.
Speaker 1: And as long as the stock prices are going up, you know, the companies are getting rewarded, not based on how much they earn, but based on how much they spend. Because everybody thinks
the biggest stuff
Speaker 1: spender is the biggest winner but they're not right now the companies that win are the companies that are selling the crap that they're buying but even those companies are going to have a lot of trouble when their customers can't buy anymore because they're broke and they can't borrow anymore and at some point the bond market is going to break
Speaker 2: there's a limit to how much money people want to lend
Speaker 2: to meta and google and and and and and uh spacex i mean spacex just the other day it was up
Speaker 1: today but it went below 137 so it was two two dollars above the ipo price down 40 percent from its post ipo high so people are starting to get worried about facebook stock why the i mean about a spacex stock why the hell would you want to buy their bonds because you don't even get much upside i
Speaker 1: one two percent above treasuries what the hell i mean why take all that risk just buy treasuries in fact if you really want to uh
Speaker 5: loan money or buy spacex bonds or buy you know meta or you know amazon bonds wait till the market breaks this is a point that george gammon made
Speaker 1: and i agreed just like what happened with stretch right
If
Speaker 1: you really wanted to buy stretch, you didn't buy them at par. You waited for the market to sell off, and then you bought them at 75 cents on the dollar. You got a deal. So if you want to lend money to these
Speaker 5: hyperscalers, don't lend it at par. Wait for the market to break because there's going to be a scare. And of course, all of our GDP right now is a function of
Speaker 1: this AI arms race. All these huge companies spending a fortune without any regard to whether or not they're ever going
Speaker 1: going to make money on these
Speaker 2: investments. Again, I believe in AI. I think AI can be a game changer. I think it could be one of the biggest factors of increased productivity, bigger than the internet. And it could be like the wheel. I mean, it's a big invention that can really improve mankind. But
Speaker 1: that doesn't mean these companies that are currently spending a fortune buying this equipment are actually going to get a positive return on their investment.
Speaker 1: The real winners from AI may be companies
Speaker 2: that nobody's even thinking about. In fact, I think the biggest winners are going to be the companies that incorporate the AI and use it to make more profits because buying the AI could end up being commoditized. There may not be a lot of profits. At the end of the day, it could be a low margin business supplying AI.
And
Speaker 2: I know it takes a lot of energy to power it now, but maybe it won't take as much in the future when people come up with a better way to do it. So all of this spending could be a complete waste. And I think we're headed for a big drop in the market. And by the way, as long as I mentioned strategy today.
Speaker 1: Saylor, again, for the third week in a row, didn't buy any Bitcoin, but he didn't sell any. Instead, he sold $467 million worth of strategy common stock to lift their cash reserves to $3 billion.
Why
Speaker 1: did he sell stock? The stock is trading at nearly a 40% discount to Bitcoin. He destroyed shareholder value with a huge negative Bitcoin yield on this transaction. Strategy shareholders would have been much better off. In fact, stretch shareholders would have been better off had strategy sold Bitcoin. Instead,
Speaker 4: Saylor decided not to sell Bitcoin
Speaker 4: to sell common stock instead which was a massive dilution for no reason but there
is a
Speaker 4: reason and the
Speaker 1: reason is he doesn't want to sell Bitcoin because he doesn't want to push the price down which shows you all the talk about these Bitcoin reserves and how they got 30 years worth of reserves is all BS he's afraid to use the reserves sailor knows if he starts really selling Bitcoin the price is gonna crash
Speaker 1: Now, the problem is it's going to crash anyway because the market realizes the bind that he's in. And even if he doesn't sell, the market is going to crash out from under him. But he is so nervous about selling Bitcoin that he's willing to sell his own stock at a massive discount. In fact, part of their new plan.
Speaker 1: Their cash reserve plan was authorizing the sale of a billion dollars worth of Bitcoin to buy back strategy shares, which they should be doing right now because of the massive discount. Well, given that they're authorized to buy back stock, why is he selling even more?
Speaker 1: You know, exacerbating the very discount that the buyback was authorized to try to reduce.
Speaker 2: It's all because he recognizes the problem that the market is still glossing over. Believe me, you know, if Bitcoiners understood the severity, Bitcoin would be much lower right now. In fact, it's amazing to me.
Speaker 2: that Bitcoin is still above 60,000. I know a lot of people regret that they didn't buy Bitcoin when they first heard about it, like me, right? I wish I'd have bought it when I first heard about it. I don't regret not buying it three, four, five years ago. But yeah, 15 years ago, sure, I should have bought it. But what's going to happen next, it's not going to be about the people who regret not buying it. It's going to be all the people who regret not selling it.
Speaker 2: People who don't sell Bitcoin at $60,000. In fact, now it's more like 64,000. I think the real resistance is about 65,000. That's kind of was the support. And now it's kind of resistance. The next level of support, you know, just a little bit below.
Speaker 2: uh, a 60, that 58,000 about there is like kind of support 65 resistance. But I think once it cracks 58, it's going to crack 50 and then it could go right to 30 or 20. Uh, but the people who don't sell it now, they're going to be the ones, uh, that are going to have a lot of regrets. Anyway, thanks for listening, everybody. Remember if you liked this podcast, give me the thumbs up, uh, leave me a comment.
And
Speaker 2: make sure and subscribe to my YouTube channel. And if you're not listening to the podcast on YouTube, if you're listening on Shift Radio, that's great. But you can still go to YouTube and subscribe. Trying to get that subscriber count. My new goal is 700,000. It's a slow-moving process on YouTube. I mean, about almost 630,000. But I want to get more subscribers. And again, subscribe everywhere. You know, I'm on TikTok. I'm on Instagram. I'm on Facebook. Uh, but my number one platform,
uh,
Speaker 2: for engagement right now other than YouTube, but where I'm constantly bringing stuff up is on X. So again, if you're not following me there, make sure and do so. And bye for now. And I'm going to be back again probably on Friday to wrap up the week and discuss day two of the Kevin War show. Bye for
Speaker 9: now.